export const warmupPassageEigthGrade = {
  key: 1,
  source: 'framingham',
  pdf_corpus1: 'HowTo/Topic',
  passage: [
    `Here's how to make the best tuna fish sandwich in the neighborhood, maybe the entire galaxy! Go to the grocery store and buy a 9 ounce can of tuna fish, celery, onions, pita bread, and mayonnaise or salad dressing. Using a spoon, `,
    'spoon half the tuna in the can into a bowl. Get some celery and onions and chop them up with a knife. When done chopping the celery and onions mix them with mayonnaise or salad dressing in a large bowl.',
    `Cut the sides off two slices of the pita bread so that each piece has an open pocket. Toast the pita bread pockets until they are warm. Don't over toast the pita pockets or you might burn them. Fill the pita`,
    `pockets with the mixed up tuna. Eat one yourself to see how yummy it is and then give one to a friend. Pretty soon the entire neighborhood will be knocking at your door to eat your yummy tuna fish sandwiches.`,
  ],
  questions: [
    {
      key: 1,
      question: 'You have to mix the tuna fish with:',
      options: [
        'Mayonnaise or salad dressing, pickles, and onions',
        'Mayonnaise or salad dressing, celery, and pickles',
        'Mayonnaise or salad dressing, celery, and onions',
        'Mayonnaise or salad dressing, cucumbers, and celery',
      ],
      answer: 'Mayonnaise or salad dressing, celery, and onions',
    },
    {
      key: 2,
      question: 'Before you fill the pockets of your pita bread with the tuna mixture:',
      options: [
        'Lightly bake the pita in the oven',
        'Warm it up in the microwave',
        `Lightly toast the pita bread but don't burn it`,
        'Heat it up on a frying pan',
      ],
      answer: `Lightly toast the pita bread but don't burn it`,
    },
    {
      key: 3,
      question: 'How much of a 9 ounce can of tuna should you scoop?',
      options: ['Half a can', 'The entire can', 'A quarter a can', 'A third of a can'],
      answer: 'Half a can',
    },
    {
      key: 4,
      question: 'What warning did the narrator give about toasting the pita bread?',
      options: [
        `Don't over toast the pita pockets or you might burn them.`,
        'Toast both sides of the pita otherwise they will over cook on one side.',
        `Don't toast the pita, it will dry out.`,
        'We never got a warning from the narrator.',
      ],
      answer: `Don't over toast the pita pockets or you might burn them.`,
    },
  ],
};

export const passagesEigthGrade = [
  {
    key: 2,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Steamboats on the Erie Canal',
    passage: [
      'During the spring of 1858, a well-to-do farmer of western New York whittled a spiral screw-propeller to help traverse the Erie Canal, one of the most important waterways that connected Lake Erie to the Hudson River. This screw-propeller allowed him to conveniently ship',
      'goods throughout the midwest of the United States. Soon after, this farmer contracted for a boat to be built that would be powered by steam. Although advised by his builders to substitute the common four-bladed propellers from older versions of boats, he stuck',
      `to his original design. With one propeller at either side of the rudder called "twin-propellers" the boat was ready for use. This boat is now known as the Charles Wack. The following season of 1859 was the most active year the Erie Canal has ever`,
      'known in regard to steam. The Charles Wack was sold to Mr. Prosser, who took out the original propellers, and substituted a modern propeller. This doubled its engine capacity. These advances in technology forever changed transportation of goods in the United States.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'The Erie Canal connected Lake Erie to the:',
        options: ['Atlantic Ocean', 'Eerie River', 'Mississippi River', 'Hudson River'],
        answer: 'Hudson River',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'The boat, Charles Wack, used ___________ propellers to in its design.',
        options: ['Twin', 'Single', 'Triple', 'No'],
        answer: 'Twin',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'The first boats on the Erie Canal were powered by:',
        options: ['Coal', 'Gasoline', 'Steam', 'Electricity'],
        answer: 'Steam',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question:
          'After the Charles Wack was sold in 1859, Mr. Prosser replaced the original propellers with:',
        options: ['High Speed propellors', 'Modern propellors', 'Turbo propellers', 'Paddles'],
        answer: 'Modern propellors',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 3,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'How to Identify Trees',
    passage: [
      'There are many ways in which the problem of identifying trees may be approached. In almost every tree there is at least one trait that marks its individuality and separates it from other trees. It may be the general form of the tree, its mode',
      'of branching, bark, bud, or fruit. It may be some variation in color, or, in the case of the evergreen trees, it may be the number and position of the needles or leaves. The pines belong to the coniferous class of trees; that is, trees',
      'that bear cones. The pines may be identified from the other coniferous trees by their leaves, which are in the form of needles two inches or more in length. The pine needles are arranged in clusters. Each species has a certain number of needles to',
      'the cluster. This is one of the simplest and most direct ways of distinguishing the different pines. In the white pine there are five needles to each cluster, in the pitch pine there are three, and in the Scotch pine there are two.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'Characters that allow you to identify different types of trees include:',
        options: [
          'Variation of color and form',
          'The number and position of needles and leaves',
          'The number of needles',
          'Variation of color and form and the number and position of needles and leaves',
        ],
        answer: 'Variation of color and form and the number and position of needles and leaves',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question:
          'One way to identify a pine tree is by noticing how the pine needles are arranged:',
        options: ['In clusters', 'Randomly', 'In groups of exactly 20', 'In random groups'],
        answer: 'In clusters',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'Coniferous trees are a class of trees that:',
        options: [
          'Bear cones',
          'Are difficult to plant',
          'Decay easily',
          'Lose pine needles in the spring',
        ],
        answer: 'Bear cones',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'A white pine has clusters of ______ pine needles.',
        options: ['25', '7', '5', '12'],
        answer: '5',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 4,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Viewing the Sun and the Stars',
    passage: [
      'The dominant member of the solar system is the sun. Its volume is more than a million times that of the earth. Its temperature is far higher than any that can be produced on the earth, even in the most efficient electric furnaces.',
      'Tools, like high powered telescopes, are used to show that the sun contains many elements, particularly metals. The stars that seem to fill the sky on a clear night are suns. Many of these stars are much larger and more brilliant than our',
      'own sun. They appear to be relatively faint points of light in the sky because of their enormous distances from us. The nearest of them is so remote that it would take more than four years for its light to come to the',
      'solar system; and others, still within the range of large telescopes, are a thousand times more distant. There are only about 5000 stars visible to the naked eye, but great photographic telescopes that are now used, show several hundreds of millions of them.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'The sun is composed of many elements including:',
        options: ['Sand', 'Hydrogen', 'Rock', 'Metal'],
        answer: 'Hydrogen',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: `Although we can view many stars with the naked eye, it would take nearly _________ years for the nearest star's light to come into our solar system.`,
        options: ['40', '4', '20', '10'],
        answer: '4',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'The volume of the sun is __________ times greater than the earth:',
        options: ['A hundred', 'A thousand', 'A billion', 'A million'],
        answer: 'A million',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question:
          'Although there are only 5000 stars visible to the naked eye, telescopes have allowed us to view hundreds of _________.',
        options: ['Thousands', 'Millions', 'Billions', 'Trillions'],
        answer: 'Millions',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 5,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: `Beethoven's Early Life`,
    passage: [
      `At age 15, young Beethoven played the organ every morning at the six o'clock mass in the Minorite church that he and his family attended. As a creative young mind, he took an interest in other composers' works. He studied Bach's compositions so`,
      `much that he was able to play the greater part of the "Well-tempered Clavichord" at twelve years old. As a boy, he was shy and reserved. Instead of playing with children his age, he began learning the art of music composition. In fact,`,
      'he is said to have written a cantata at the age of ten. When he was seventeen he went to Vienna, Austria. Here, he met Mozart who was at the height of his fame. On his first meeting with Mozart, Beethoven performed a',
      `composition influenced by the great composer. In fact, he played with such an effect and such emotion that when he finished, Mozart made a remark that people should, "Pay attention to him. He will make a noise in the world some day".`,
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'One of the composers who Beethoven admired was:',
        options: ['Isaac', 'Chopin', 'Bach', 'Haydn'],
        answer: 'Bach',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: `Beethoven's first meeting with Mozart was in:`,
        options: ['Italy', 'Vienna', 'Austria', 'Romania'],
        answer: 'Vienna',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'Beethoven was said to have written his first cantata at age:',
        options: ['17', '10', '23', '7'],
        answer: '10',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'Mozart made a remark about Beethoven saying that people should:',
        options: [
          'Ignore him',
          'Pay attention to him',
          'Acknowledge his accomplishment',
          'Listen to more sophisticated music',
        ],
        answer: 'Pay attention to him',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 6,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: `Benjamin Franklin's Great Inventions`,
    passage: [
      'Benjamin Franklin was a great inventor. He believed that the electricity in a Leyden Jar, an electrical device consisting of a glass jar and metal foil which could store static electricity, was the same thing as the lightning we see in a thunderstorm.',
      'He made a kite out of a silk handkerchief, and fastened a sharp iron point to the upright stick of the kite. One day, when a thunder-storm was coming, Franklin and his son went out to the fields. The kite was raised; then',
      'Franklin tied an iron key to the lower end of the string. After waiting some time, he felt certain that the electricity was coming down the string. He put his knuckle close to the key, and a spark flew out. Next, he took',
      'his Leyden Jar and collected the electricity in that. He had made two great discoveries that day: he found out that electricity and lightning are the same thing, and he had also found how to fill his Leyden jar directly from the clouds.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'A Leyden jar is:',
        options: [
          'A jar for storing perishable goods',
          'A jar holding valuables',
          'An antique lightbulb',
          'An electrical device that held electricity',
        ],
        answer: 'An electrical device that held electricity',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Franklin discovered that electricity is:',
        options: [
          'Similar to lightning',
          'A different makeup than lightning',
          'Entirely different than lightning',
          'The same as lightning',
        ],
        answer: 'The same as lightning',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'Franklin used the following items in his first experiment:',
        options: [
          'A kite, a key, and a Leyden jar',
          'A kite, a string, and a rod',
          'A single Leyden jar',
          'A kite, a key, string, and a Leyden jar',
        ],
        answer: 'A kite, a key, string, and a Leyden jar',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'The passage states that Benjamin Franklin was a _____________:',
        options: ['Famous inventor', 'Great inventor', 'Great scientist', 'Famous scientist'],
        answer: 'Great inventor',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 7,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'The Baltimore and Ohio Railroad',
    passage: [
      `On February 12, 1827, two men - Philip E. Thomas and George Brown - held a meeting to determine the best way to restore trade that had been lost in the Baltimore region. The result was a petition to open "The Baltimore`,
      `and Ohio Railroad Company" which would have the right to build and operate a railroad from the city of Baltimore to the Ohio River. The construction of the railroad began on July 4, 1828. Charles Carroll, the only surviving signer of the`,
      `Declaration of Independence, was invited to lay the first stone down to signify the start of construction. He said, "I consider this among the most important acts of my life, second only to my signing the Declaration of Independence" By 1832, the`,
      'whole line had been opened, making the railroad a total of seventy-two miles in all. By 1842, the railroad had more than 500 miles of track. This construction began a new era of transportation and efficiency for the American people.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'Philip E. Thomas and George Brown were in charge of:',
        options: [
          'Building a canal through Maryland',
          'Pioneering building a railroad from Baltimore to Cleveland, Ohio',
          'Building a railroad from Washington DC to the Ohio River',
          'Pioneering building a railroad from Baltimore to the Ohio River',
        ],
        answer: 'Pioneering building a railroad from Baltimore to the Ohio River',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question:
          'Charles Carroll, an honored guest at the groundbreaking for the railroad, was one of the men who signed the:',
        options: ['Constitution', 'American Flag', 'Bill of Rights', 'Declaration of Independence'],
        answer: 'Declaration of Independence',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'By 1842, the railroad had more than ________ miles of track:',
        options: ['750', '1000', '5000', '500'],
        answer: '500',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question:
          'he construction of the Baltimore-Ohio River Railroad was considered to be____________ by the American people.',
        options: ['A success', 'A failure', 'A nuisance', 'We never learned it'],
        answer: 'A success',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 8,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Water Vessels in the Pueblo Region',
    passage: [
      `The Pueblo region of the United States is historically known as an area where pottery was practiced and worked to perfection. The Pueblos' first necessity of life is the transportation and preservation of water. In an effort to transport water, the people`,
      'once tried using skins of animals, but this was unsuccessful as the water sitting in animal skins in a hot climate would contaminate it. Later, a more successful water vessel was created. They were tubes of wood or sections of canes. Although',
      'these canes grew in abundance in this area, another, more effective water vessel came into play. Gourds, which also grew in abundance in these places, were better shapes and held a larger volume of water. To help protect and transport the gourd,',
      'it was encased in a net of coarse wicker like rope which was made out of yucca leaves or of flexible splints. The use of this wicker with water-vessels points toward the development of the water-tight basketry of the southwest.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'The first vessel used to transport water was made out of:',
        options: ['Canvas', 'Wood', 'Leaves', 'Animal skin'],
        answer: 'Animal skin',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'The development of baskets resulted in the water vessel being:',
        options: ['Unbreakable', 'More durable', 'Temperature regulated', 'Water-tight'],
        answer: 'Water-tight',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'A more effective vessel, which held a larger volume of water, was the:',
        options: ['Basket', 'Animal Skin', 'Tube', 'Gourd'],
        answer: 'Gourd',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'The use of baskets as a water vessel were most likely:',
        options: [
          'Used by many people',
          'Only used by some',
          'Rarely used',
          'Seasonally important',
        ],
        answer: 'Used by many people',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 9,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Navajo Houses',
    passage: [
      'The Navajo reservation is a large area of land in the northeastern part of Arizona and the northwestern corner of New Mexico. The Navajo recognize two distinct classes of hogans, winter huts and summer shelters. Winter huts are a staple of Navajo culture.',
      `On the outside, they resemble mounds of earth hollowed out. However, they are warm and comfortable. Decoration on the inside or outside of the houses is uncommon, yet, the hogans are usually referred to as "beautiful". The rules for building a winter house`,
      'do not apply to the summer huts. The summer hut is one of the most primitive and simple shelters the Navajo builds. 4 to 5 feet of branches are piled on three sides of a circle 15 or 20 feet in diameter. A',
      'fire is built in the center and blankets are thrown over outstanding branches here and there, creating a great amount of shade during the hot summer days. Although it is a makeshift shelter, it is effective to escape from the brutal heat.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'Winter huts are described as:',
        options: ['Rough', 'Earthy', 'Old', 'Beautiful'],
        answer: 'Beautiful',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Summer huts are usually:',
        options: ['Permanent homes', 'Beautiful', 'Earthy', 'Makeshift'],
        answer: 'Makeshift',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'What shape are the summer huts?',
        options: ['Square', 'Rectangle', 'Oval', 'Circle'],
        answer: 'Circle',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'The land on the Navajo reservation can be characterized as:',
        options: ['Plentiful', 'Rocky', 'Sandy plains', 'Clear meadows'],
        answer: 'Sandy plains',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 10,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Into the Unknown',
    passage: [
      'It was a white caravan that looked down from the crest of the mountains upon the green wilderness called Kentucky. The travelers saw the land of hope before them, a wide sweep of rolling country, covered with trees. They were alive with interest and',
      'curiosity, because this unknown land was to be their home, but no one was more eager than Henry Ware, a strong, fifteen year old boy. The long journey from their old home in Maryland had been a delight to Henry. There were no tearful',
      `goodbyes as he left. Henry's entire family came on the journey: his mother, brother and younger sister were in the fourth wagon from the right, and his father stood beside it. As they moved forward, Henry felt like he was coming home, like he`,
      'had seen this place before. The forests and the mountains were a friendly sight. He seemed to breathe a newer and fresher air than that of Maryland that he left behind, and his mind expanded with the thought of what was to come.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'This story takes place as travellers moved through:',
        options: ['Nebraska', 'Colorado', 'Virginia', 'Kentucky'],
        answer: 'Kentucky',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Henry traveled with:',
        options: ['His rifle', 'His parents', 'His friends', 'His entire family'],
        answer: 'His entire family',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'How old was Henry?',
        options: ['14 years old', '16 years old', '17 years old', '15 years old'],
        answer: '15 years old',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'As he arrived in Kentucky, he started to feel:',
        options: [
          'Like he belonged there',
          'That it was dangerous',
          'A longing for another adventure',
          'Uneasy',
        ],
        answer: 'Like he belonged there',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 11,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Journey to The Coral Islands',
    passage: [
      'It was a bright, warm day when our ship sailed for the regions of the south. There were a number of boys on the ship, but two of them were my favorites. Jack Martin was a tall, broad-shouldered boy of eighteen, with a',
      'handsome, good-humoured face. My other companion was Peterkin Jay. He was little, quick, funny, mischievous, and about fourteen years old. Days dragged on as our friendship grew, and after a while, the days started to blur together. When we approached Cape Horn, the',
      'weather became very cold and stormy, and the sailors began to tell stories about the furious gales and the dangers of that terrible cape. Nevertheless we passed the dreaded cape without much rough weather. At last we came among the Coral Islands of',
      'the Pacific; and I shall never forget the delight when I looked upon the pure white, dazzling shores, and the rich green palm-trees. The three of us longed to be on land once again. Our wish was granted sooner than we expected.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'The name of the narrator is:',
        options: ['Jack', 'Petekin', 'Michael', 'We never learn it'],
        answer: 'We never learn it',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'The ship traveled around:',
        options: ['Cape Coral', 'Cape May', 'Cape Cod', 'Cape Horn'],
        answer: 'Cape Horn',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'The ship ended up in the:',
        options: ['Atlantic Ocean', 'Gulf of Mexico', 'Indian Ocean', 'Pacific Ocean'],
        answer: 'Pacific Ocean',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'Cape Horn was rumored to be:',
        options: ['Calm', 'Warm', 'Dangerous', 'Magical'],
        answer: 'Dangerous',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 12,
    source: 'katie (gutenberg)',
    pd_corpus2: 'Phil the Fiddler',
    passage: [
      `"Viva Garibaldi!" sang a young Italian boy in an uptown street. He held a battered violin that looked as if it had been used for generations. The young singer was twelve years old, but small for his age. In spite of the dirt, his`,
      'face was strikingly handsome, especially when he smiled. He was always smiling in spite of hardships, which were many in his life. Phil had been wandering the streets, singing and playing for two hours. However, he had not received a penny. He was about',
      `to change his position when the basement door of one of the houses opened, and a servant came out. "My young master wants to hear you play on your fiddle," said the servant. "He's sick, and can't come out." Phil followed through the giant`,
      'house up to the parlor where the sick boy sat. The little fiddler, who had never been invited into a fine house before, looked with admiration at the handsome furniture. He knew that this could be a moment that changed his life.',
    ],
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: `Phil's violin was:`,
        options: ['New and pristine', 'An antique', 'Slightly used', 'Old and battered'],
        answer: 'Old and battered',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Phil was singing and playing the violin in order to:',
        options: ['Find fame', 'Gain experience', 'Find a musical partner', 'Make money'],
        answer: 'Make money',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'How old was Phil?',
        options: ['10 years old', '11 years old', 'His age is not mentioned', '12 years old'],
        answer: '12 years old',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'Phil lived with:',
        options: ['His parents', '40 other boys', 'Himself', 'No one'],
        answer: '40 other boys',
      },
    ],
  },
];

export const passagesTwelthGrade = [
  {
    key: 0,
    passage_number: 117,
    passage:
      'The Voting Rights Act, signed into law by President Lyndon Baines Johnson (1908-73) on August 6, 1965, aimed to overcome legal barriers at the state and local levels that prevented African Americans from exercising their right to vote under the 15th Amendment (1870) to the Constitution of the United States. The act significantly widened the franchise and is considered among the most far-reaching pieces of civil rights legislation in U.S. history. Lyndon Johnson assumed the presidency in November 1963 upon the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. In the presidential race of 1964, Johnson was elected in a landslide victory and used this mandate to push for legislation he believed would improve the American way of life, including stronger voting-rights laws. In 1965, at the time of the passage of the Voting Rights Act, there were six African-American members of the U.S. House of Representatives and no Black members of the U.S. Senate. By 1971, there were 13 Black members of the House and one Black member of the Senate. After the U.S. Civil War (1861-65), the 15th Amendment, ratified in 1870, prohibited states from denying a male citizen the right to vote based on “race, color or previous condition of servitude.” Nevertheless, in the ensuing decades, various discriminatory practices were used to prevent African Americans, particularly those in the South, from exercising their right to vote. During the 1950s and 1960s, voting rights activists in the South were subjected to various forms of mistreatment and violence in response to their actions to claim their legal rights. One event that outraged many Americans occurred on March 7, 1965, when peaceful participants in a voting rights march from Selma, Alabama, to the state capitol in Montgomery, were brutally attacked on the Edmund Pettus Bridge. This event, among others, galvanized support for the Voting Rights Act which was subsequently signed into law by President Johnson.',
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'What was the purpose of the Voting Rights Act of 1965?',
        options: [
          'To give women the right the vote',
          'To lower the voting age to 18',
          'To prevent voting by people without proper ID',
          'To protect the right of African American voters from local interference',
        ],
        answer: 'To protect the right of African American voters from local interference',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Which president championed the Voting Rights Act of 1965?',
        options: ['Richard Nixon', 'John Kennedy', 'Barack Obama', 'Lyndon Johnson'],
        answer: 'Lyndon Johnson',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'What right did the 15th Amendment provide?',
        options: [
          'It gave white women the right to vote',
          'It outlawed slavery',
          'It gave 18-year-olds the right to vote',
          'It granted all men over 21 years old the right to vote',
        ],
        answer: 'It granted all men over 21 years old the right to vote',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'How were voting rights activists treated in the 1950s and 1960s?',
        options: [
          'They were dismissed as unserious',
          'They received little attention by the press',
          'They were given widespread support. ',
          'They were subjected to violent attacks.',
        ],
        answer: 'They were subjected to violent attacks.',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 1,
    passage_grade: '12th Grade',
    passage_number: 118,
    passage:
      'During the last ice age, between 13,000 and 12,600 years ago, the Clovis culture appeared in North America. The Clovis made and used distinctive stone-tipped spears to hunt mammoth, bison and mastodon. Until recently, all that archeologists knew about the Clovis people came from studying their tools, which have been unearthed at many sites across the continental United States. Now, DNA analysis of a single human skeleton--that of a one-year-old boy buried in a rocky field in modern-day Montana--has allowed scientists to link the Clovis culture to Native Americans throughout the Western Hemisphere. Construction crews first discovered the ancient remains of an infant in 1968 on private property owned by the Anzick family in western Montana. Dubbed Anzick-1, the one-year-old boy is the only human skeleton that has been identified as a member of the widespread, sophisticated Ice-Age culture known as the Clovis. Now, a team of scientists has succeeded in mapping the infant’s DNA, in the oldest genome sequence of an American individual ever performed. According to their findings, published in the journal Nature in February 2014, the Clovis people are direct ancestors of many Native Americans now living in North America, and can be linked to many native peoples in Central and South America as well. Up to this point, all that scientists studying the Clovis People had to go on were the stone and bone tools that have been found at sites ranging from Washington State to Florida, along with many states in between. By sequencing the genome of the infant recovered at the Anzick site, the international team of researchers gained the most vivid insight yet about who these people might actually have been.',
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'Where were the stone and bone tools used by the Clovis culture found?',
        options: [
          'In Siberia, Alaska, and Northern Canada',
          'In the Northeastern part of the US and Canada',
          'In the southwestern US',
          'Across the continental US',
        ],
        answer: 'Across the continental US',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question:
          'How did scientists determine that the Clovis people are ancestors of Native Americans?',
        options: [
          'By linking DNA from different Native American groups to each other',
          'By comparing the DNA of the Clovis infant found with that of Neanderthals',
          'By unearthing similar tools used by both groups of people',
          'By mapping the genome of the Clovis infant and comparing the DNA with modern Native Americans',
        ],
        answer:
          'By mapping the genome of the Clovis infant and comparing the DNA with modern Native Americans',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'What did the discovery of Anzick-1 tell scientists about the Clovis people?',
        options: [
          'The Anzick family are direct descendants from the Clovis people. ',
          'The Clovis people were closely related to peoples of far-eastern Siberia',
          'The Clovis people shared significant Neanderthal DNA',
          'The Clovis culture is linked to Native Americans. ',
        ],
        answer: 'The Clovis culture is linked to Native Americans.',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'What were the Clovis people known for?',
        options: [
          'Their use of furs and skins from mammoth, bison, and mastodon',
          'Their use of cloves in cooking and medicinal recipes',
          'Their extensive skills at farming and ranching',
          'Their use of stone-tipped spears to hunt mammoth, bison, and mastodon ',
        ],
        answer: 'Their use of stone-tipped spears to hunt mammoth, bison, and mastodon ',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 2,
    passage_number: 119,
    passage:
      'Water makes up nearly three-quarters of the Earth’s surface, but it does more than just cover our planet - it also plays a vital role in shaping the land. Consider the Grand Canyon. Measuring 277 miles long, 18 miles wide and more than 1 mile deep, it is considered one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World and attracts more than 5 million visitors per year. This geological marvel was created by the waters of the Colorado River through the processes of weathering and erosion. Weathering is the process by which moving water breaks down soil, rock and minerals, and erosion is the process by which the flowing water transports soil and rock from one spot and deposits it elsewhere. The two processes often occur in conjunction. Weathering and erosion are very slow processes. Geologists believe the Colorado River has been flowing through the Grand Canyon for at least 17 million years, and it has been gradually shaping the canyon this entire time. The flowing water of the river and its tributaries has carved away at the rock of the Colorado Plateau, creating the sight we are familiar with today. Caves and caverns are another example of weathering and erosion. Limestone caves, such as the Carlsbad Caverns in New Mexico, are formed when rainwater mixes with carbon dioxide in the ground, forming an acid, which dissolves the limestone. Sea caves, which can be found along coastlines, are formed when powerful waves crash against the shore and break away chunks of rock. Ice caves are formed when glaciers melt, and the ice melt flows across the ground as a stream. You don’t have to travel very far to see the effects of weathering and erosion for yourself, though, the effects of weathering and erosion are evident almost everywhere in the shapes of rocks, and even the aging of buildings.',
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'What can happen when glaciers melt?',
        options: [
          'Rock caves form',
          'Sea caves form',
          'Icebergs can break loose ',
          'Ice caves form',
        ],
        answer: 'Ice caves form',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'How are caves and caverns formed?',
        options: [
          'By heavy rainfall ',
          'By the movement of tectonic plates',
          'By bats scratching away stone',
          'By weathering and erosion',
        ],
        answer: 'By weathering and erosion',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'Which best explains the relationship between weathering and erosion?',
        options: [
          'Weathering happens before erosion. ',
          'Erosion happens before weathering.',
          'Weathering only happens if erosion does not happen. ',
          'Weathering and erosion happen at the same time.',
        ],
        answer: 'Weathering and erosion happen at the same time.',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'How long is the Grand Canyon?',
        options: ['180 miles', '500 miles', '7 miles', '277 miles'],
        answer: '277 miles',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 3,
    passage_number: 120,
    passage:
      'Born in Litchfield, Connecticut, Harriet Beecher was the seventh child of the Reverend Lyman Beecher, a Congregational minister and moral reformer, and Roxanna Foote Beecher. She was schooled at the Pierce Academy and at her sister Catharine Beecher’s Hartford Female Seminary, where she also taught. She moved with the family to Cincinnati in 1832, when her father was appointed president of Lane Theological Seminary. The spectacle of chattel slavery across the Ohio River in Kentucky and its effects on the commercial interests of white Cincinnati residents moved her deeply. In 1836, she married Calvin Ellis Stowe, professor of biblical literature at Lane. The death of a son in 1849 led her away from her father’s Calvinism and gave supremacy in her views to the redemptive spirit of Christian love. By 1850, the family had moved to Maine, where, in response to the Fugitive Slave Act of that year, Stowe wrote Uncle Tom’s Cabin (1852), her most celebrated work. Sentimental and realistic by turns, the novel explored the cruelties of chattel slavery in the Upper and Lower South and exposed the moral ironies in the legal, religious, and social arguments of white apologists. The immense impact of the novel (it sold 300,000 copies in its first year) was unexpected. Antislavery fiction had never sold well, but Uncle Tom’s Cabin became a sensation, a major success, and an enormous influence on the antislavery movement. Stowe was not an established writer, and few would have expected a woman to gain a popular hearing on the great political question of the day. Some female abolitionists had shocked the decorum of the 1840s by speaking at public gatherings, but they were widely resented. The success of Uncle Tom’s Cabin went far toward legitimizing, if not indeed creating, a role for women in public affairs.',
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question: 'How did Uncle Tom’s Cabin impact the role of women?',
        options: [
          'After it was published, women were given more credence in literary circles',
          'Women took on more prominent roles in the Calvinist church',
          'It did not change the place of women in contemporary society',
          'The success of the book helped legitimize women’s place in public affairs',
        ],
        answer: 'The success of the book helped legitimize women’s place in public affairs',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'What was Uncle Tom’s Cabin about?',
        options: [
          'The death of Harriet’s son',
          'Life in Maine',
          'Thomas Jefferson’s relationship with Sally Hemings',
          'The cruelties of slavery in the South',
        ],
        answer: 'The cruelties of slavery in the South',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'What did Harriet turn away from in 1849?',
        options: [
          'Her husband Calvin',
          'Chattel slavery',
          'All religion',
          'Her father’s Calvinism',
        ],
        answer: 'Her father’s Calvinism',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'Why did Harriet Beecher move to Cincinnati?',
        options: [
          'Her mother left her father, and took Harriet with her',
          'She no longer wanted to live in Connecticut',
          'She was going to attend Hartford Female Seminary',
          'Her father was appointed president of Lane Theological Seminary',
        ],
        answer: 'Her father was appointed president of Lane Theological Seminary',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    key: 4,
    passage_number: 121,
    passage:
      'One of the most fascinating leaders of the Haitian Revolution, and perhaps the best known, is Toussaint Louverture. Born a slave but given his freedom at around age 30, he worked as a coachman and a manager on the Breda plantation near Cap Français. He was able to read and write in both French and Kreyòl, having been taught by his godfather, Pierre Baptiste (whom some historians believe may actually have been his father). Loverture was 56 years old when the French Revolution broke out, and over the course of the next 10 years he played three major—and very different—roles in the history of Haiti. He was a military leader who united the revolutionary forces of the whole island of Saint-Domingue and led them to victory. He was an economic developer who instituted the plans for rebuilding Haiti’s ravaged economy. And finally, as a statesman, he created the first constitution of the new country. In each of these roles, he was both successful and controversial. Loverture’s military career began as a lieutenant in the insurgent forces, and he wore a Spanish uniform in his initial military campaigns. Spain had offered support to the cause of the insurgents, offering them armaments and the backing of the Spanish king. But after the French made a proclamation of general emancipation of slaves, Toussaint switched uniforms and continued to fight, now as a Frenchman, helping drive the Spanish and the British out of Saint-Domingue and secure it as a French possession. So, in the first phase of his career, he led a united group of insurrectionists to victory and established Saint-Domingue as a colony of free men, but still under French control.',
    questions: [
      {
        key: 1,
        question:
          'What country controlled Haiti at the end of the first phase of Toussaint’s career?',
        options: ['Haiti', 'Britain', 'Spain', 'France'],
        answer: 'France',
      },
      {
        key: 2,
        question: 'Who did Toussaint fight for first?',
        options: ['The Americans', 'The British', 'The French', 'The Spanish'],
        answer: 'The Spanish',
      },
      {
        key: 3,
        question: 'What roles did Toussaint Loverture play in the Haitian Revolution?',
        options: [
          'Military leader, field medic, and sharpshooter',
          'Military leader, engineer, and builder',
          'Military leader, professor, and soldier',
          'Military leader, economic developer, and statesman',
        ],
        answer: 'Military leader, economic developer, and statesman',
      },
      {
        key: 4,
        question: 'Who taught Toussaint Louverture how to read?',
        options: [
          'Alexander Hamilton',
          'Jean-Bertrand Aristede',
          'The Spanish army',
          'Pierre Baptiste',
        ],
        answer: 'Pierre Baptiste',
      },
    ],
  },
];
export const warmupPassageTwelthGrade = {
  key: 1,
  passage_grade: '12th Grade',
  passage_number: 116,
  passage:
    'In the Mesa Verde National Park in Colorado, one of the most amazing sights in the United States is dug into the side of a mountain. Sandy-colored towers, walls and rooms sit there, overlooking the park. They have no roofs, but the structures are protected by the overhanging cliff. Eight centuries after their construction, they are in excellent condition and remain one of the most intriguing archaeological sites in the country. Who built these fabulous dwellings? Why did they choose to dig them into the face of the rock itself? When did they live, and how did their civilization fade? Although not all of those questions have definite answers, archeologists have discovered much about these long-ago Native Americans. The largest of their dwellings, Cliff Palace, was discovered on December 18, 1888, by a pair of Colorado cowboys who were riding the mesa in search of missing cattle. They spied the crumbling structures through the driving snow and rode their horses toward one of the most intriguing finds in archeological history. Cliff Palace and the other cliff dwellings were constructed by the Ancestral Pueblo people, a group comprised of several Native American tribes whose descendants include the Hopi, Zuni and Acoma people. The Ancestral Pueblo people lived in and around the American Southwest and their history goes back to as early as 100 A.D., during a period known as "Late Basketmaker II," due to the fine woven baskets produced during this period. Over the next thousand years, the people of the Southwest settled down gradually. They stopped living in caves and shallow pits, and began building homes. They moved from a strictly hunter-gatherer culture to one increasingly dependent on agriculture.',
  questions: [
    {
      key: 1,
      question: 'What is Mesa Verde National Park known for?',
      options: [
        'Being located in Colorado',
        'The number of mountains there',
        'The houses there have no roofs',
        'Rooms built into the sides of the mountains',
      ],
      answer: 'Rooms built into the sides of the mountains',
    },
    {
      key: 2,
      question: 'Who discovered Cliff Palace?',
      options: [
        'A pair of archaeologists',
        'A pair of hunters',
        'The Ancestral Pueblo people',
        'A pair of Colorado cowboys',
      ],
      answer: 'A pair of Colorado cowboys',
    },
    {
      key: 3,
      question: 'Who is responsible for constructing Cliff Palace?',
      options: [
        'No one knows for sure',
        'Only the Hopi tribe',
        'A pair of Colorado cowboys',
        'The Ancestral Pueblo people',
      ],
      answer: 'The Ancestral Pueblo people',
    },
    {
      key: 4,
      question: 'How did the lives of Native Americans change in the Southwest?',
      options: [
        'Instead of making baskets, they began to make homes',
        'Instead of being dependent on agriculture, they became a hunter-gatherer culture',
        'Instead of living in homes, they began living in caves and shallow pits',
        'Instead of being a hunter-gatherer culture, they became more dependent on agriculture',
      ],
      answer:
        'Instead of being a hunter-gatherer culture, they became more dependent on agriculture',
    },
  ],
};
